<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Himachal Pradesh</string>
    <string name="brief_intro">"
                        Himachal Pradesh - meaning Abode of Snow,is a state of India located in North India.It is bordered by Jammu and Kashmir on the north, Punjab and Chandigarh on the west, Haryana on the southwest, Uttarakhand on the southeast, and the Tibet Autonomous Region on the east.At its southernmost point, it also touches the state of Uttar Pradesh.The name was coined from the Sanskrit—Him means 'snow' and achal means 'land' or 'abode'—by Acharya Diwakar Datt Sharma, one of the state's eminent Sanskrit scholars.

                        Coordinates (Shimla): 31°6′12″N 77°10′20″
                        Statehood :	          25 January 1971
                        Capitals:	          Shimla, Dharamshala (Second Capital in Winter)
                        Districts:	          12
                        Divisions:	          3 (Kangra, Mandi, Shimla)
                        Sub-Divisions:	      62
                        Blocks:     	      78
                        Tehsils:    	      145
                        Lok Sabha Seats:      4
                        Rajya Sabha Seats:	  3
                        Assembly Constituencies:	68

                                • Governor:	Acharya Dev Vrat
                                • Chief Justice:	Justice Sanjay Karol
                                • Chief Minister:	Virbhadra Singh (INC)
                                • Legislature:	Unicameral (68 seats)
                                • Parliamentary constituency:	4
</string>
    <string name="title_activity_detailed">More Details</string>
    <string name="district_brief">"
        below is the list of 12 districts, click on button to know more about these"</string>
    <string name="rivers_brief">"There are 5 major rivers flowing through Himachal Pradesh
        • Beas
        • Chenab
        • Ravi
        • Satluj - longest river in H.P
        • Yamuna - shortest river in H.P



    "</string>
    <string name="history_brief">"The region of Himachal Pradesh was called 'Deva Bhoomi ' (the land of the gods). From the early period of its history it was inhabited by tribes like the Koilis, Halis, Dagis, Dhaugris, Dasa, Khasas, Kinnars and Kirats. The Aryan influence in kangra Fort this area of India dates to the period before the Rigveda. Sankar Varma, the king of Kashmir exercised his influence over regions of Himachal Pradesh in about 883 AD. This region witnessed the invasion of Mahmud of Ghazni in 1009AD, who during that period invaded and looted the wealth from the temples in the North of India. In about 1043AD the Rajputs ruled over this territory. Known for its vibrant and exquisite natural scenery it received the royal patronage of the Mughal rulers who erected several works of art as an appreciation of this land. In 1773 AD the Rajputs under Sansar Chand possessed this region, till the attack by Maharaja Ranjit Singh in 1804 which crushed the Rajput power here. The Gurkhas who migrated from Nepal captured this area and devastated it. In about the early 19th century the British exercised their influence and annexed the areas of Shimla after the Gurkha War of 1815-16. It became a centrally administered territory in 1948 with the integration of 31 hill states and received additional regions added to it in 1966.
        "</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rivers">Rivers</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bilaspur">bilaspurActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_chamba">chambaActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hamirpur">hamirpurActivity</string>
    <string name="riverssummary">"
            A. Yamuna
                1. The Eastern most river is Yamuna and mythical associated with the Sun God
                2. Yamuna enters in H.P.at Khoder Majra (Sirmaur)
                3. Tons rises from Valley of Har-ki dun (Feeder stream ‘Supin’ and Rupin )
                4. Tons joins Yamuna at an place Kalsi (Place in Dehradun valley)
                5. The river divides the Sirmaur district into two equal parts known as Giri (Cis –Giri and Trans-Giri)
                6. Giri joins the Yamuna in Paonta below Mokkampur
                7. The human settlement that have sprung up along the Giri river are Yashwantnagar ,Dadahu(Rrnuka), Sataun
                8. Pabber is the tributary of Gir
                9. Pabber river rises from Chandernahan lake near Chansal peak in Rohru (Dhauladhar range)
                10. Giri river rises from Kupar peak near Jubbal
                11. The Bata river originates from Dharthi range(lower slope of Nahan ridge)
                12. Yamuna finally drained into Bay of Bengal

            B. Satluj
                1. Longest river of H.P. Satluj
                2. Satluj enters in Himachal from Tibet near a village NAMGIA at a place called Shipki-la (6608 m)
                3. The river freezes occasionally in winter Spiti (tributary of Satluj)
                4. Main settlements on Spiti bank are Hansi and Dhankar Gompa
                5. Baspa river originates from Baspa Hill
                6. Satluj leaves Kinnaur district and entered in dist. Shimla at Chauhra
                7. Satluj touches Kullu dist. At Nirmand tehsil (opposite to Rampur tehsil)
                8. Satluj enters Mandi district at Firnu
                9. Tributaries of Satluj in distt. Mandi Sinu,Bahlu Katlu, Behna ,Siman ,Bantrehr,Khadel,Bhagmati
                10. Satluj enters Bilaspur district at Dehar
                11. Satluj leaves Himachal and entered Punjab at Bhakra
                12. Important hydroelectric projest located on satluj are Prestigious Bhakra Dam , Prestigious Nathpa Jhakri , Rongtong , Sanjay Vidyut Pariyojna (Bhaba), Andhra, Binwa, Bassi, Baspa stage1 and 2, Ghanvi Project
                13. River known as the brother of Baspa Satluj
                14. Flood in river Satluj devastated Bilaspur town in 1762A.D.
                15. Villages got submerged during the formation of Bhakra Dam 256
                16. Satluj finally drained into Indus

            C. Beas
                1. Districts on the bank of Beas river Kullu , Mandi , Hamirpur and Kangra
                2. Beas leaves Himachal and entered Punjab at Murthal
                3. Tirthan river join Beas at Larji
                4. Tirthan rises from Pir-Panjal range
                5. Main tributary of Beas is Parvati river join Beas at Shamshi
                6. Sainj river join the Beas river at Larji
                7. Beas enters Mandi district at Bajaura
                8. Beas leaves Kullu district at Nagwain
                9. The river which was known as ‘River of Sorrow ‘of Punjab but after constructed of Pon Dam it has now become a “Harbinger of Prosperity” is Beas
                10. The place where ‘Beas Rishi’ and ‘Beas Kund meat to form RIVER BEAS Palachan village
                11. Water of Beas river has been diverted at pandoh through a tunnel so as to merge with Satluj at Slapper

            D. Ravi And Chenab
                1. Chamba is situated on the right bank of the river Ravi
                2. Ravi leave Chamba and entered Punjab at Kheri
                3. The name given to river Ravi by Greek historian of Alexander is Hydraster
                4. Ravi merged in Chenab in Pakistan
                5. Chandra and Bhaga meet to form river Chenab at Tandi (Lahaul)
                6. Chenab enters Pangi Valley of Chenab district at Rihund
                7. In H.P. gold is found in the river Chandrabhaga
                8. River Chenab finally joins the Arabian sea

            E. Other Rivers
                1. Swan river is in district Una
                2. River known as ‘River of Sorrow’in Una Swan
                3. Old name of river Swan is Som Bhadra
                4. Imala and Vimla river valley is in Karsog
                5. River imla rises in Mahun Dhong
                6. Vimla river rises in Gudha
                7. Imla and Vimla rivers meet Satluj in Karsog at Parlog
                8. Greek used to call river Chenab as Asisenes
                9. Chenab leaves Chamba and entered Jammu and Kashmir at Sansari Nala
                10. The river Beas joins the satluj at Har –ka –Patun
                11. The local name of rivers Chandra and Bhaga are:-
                    Chandra-rangoli
                    Bhaga – Gara(punn)
                12. The largest river in term of amount of water is Chenab
                13. The place near Dalhousie from where one can have a full view on a clear day of three main river of Himachal namely Beas ,Ravi and Chenab Dain Kund
     "
    </string>
</resources>
